There are a few things that all of us need.
هناك بعض الأشياء التي تمثل حوجة مشتركة لنا جميعاً.
We all need air to breathe.
نحتاج جميعنا الهواء لنتنفس.
We need clean water to drink.
نحتاج جميعنا الماء العذب لنشرب.
We need food to eat. We need shelter and love.
نحتاج الطعام لنأكل. كما نحتاج المسكن والحب.
You know. Love is great, too.
كما تعلمون، الحب جميل أيضاً.
And we all need a safe place to pee.
كما أننا نحتاج إلى مكان آمن نقضي فيه حاجتنا.
(Laughter) Yeah?
(ضحك) أليس كذلك؟
As a trans person who doesn't fit neatly into the gender binary,
كشخص متحول جنسياً مثلي لا ينسجم مع نظام الجنس الثنائي،
if I could change the world tomorrow
إذا ما أتيح لي فرصة تغيير العالم غداً
to make it easier for me to navigate,
لجعل الأمر أكثر سهولة بالنسبة لي للتنقل،
the very first thing I would do
سيكون أول شيء أفعله
is blink and create single stall, gender-neutral bathrooms
أن سأغمز وآتي بحجرة منفصلة؛ حمامات محايدة للجنس.
in all public places.
في كل الأماكن العامة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Trans people and trans issues,
حظي الأشخاص المتحولون جنسياً وقضاياهم،
they've been getting a lot of mainstream media attention lately.
على تغطية إعلامية مكثفة في الأونة الأخيرة.
And this is a great and necessary thing,
وهذا شيء عظيم ومهم أيضاً،
but most of that attention has been focused
ولكن جلَّ تلك التغطية تركَّزت
on a very few individuals,
على قلة قليلة من الأفراد،
most of whom are kinda rich
السواد الأعظم منهم من الأثرياء
and pretty famous,
والمشاهير،
and probably don't have to worry that much anymore about where they're going to pee
ولايهتمون غالباً بأين سيقضون حاجتهم
in between classes at their community college,
بين الدروس خلال تواجدهم في الكلية،
or where they're going to get changed into their gym strip
أو أين سيغيرون ملابسهم الرياضية
at their public high school.
خلال تواجدهم في المدرسة الثانوية.
Fame and money insulates these television star trans people
يعزل المال والشهرة نجوم الشاشة هؤلاء
from most of the everyday challenges
عن أغلب التحديات اليومية
that the rest of us have to tackle on a daily basis.
والتي يتوجب على أغلبنا التصدي لها بشكل يومي.
Public bathrooms.
ألا وهي الحمامات العامة.
They've been a problem for me since as far back as I can remember,
كانت مشكلة بالنسبة لي منذ أمد بعيد،
first when I was just a little baby tomboy
بدايةً منذ أن كنت فتاة مسترجلة صغيرة
and then later as a masculine-appearing, predominantly estrogen-based organism.
ثم بعد ذلك كصاحبة مظهر ذكوري، قائم أساساً على هرمون الإٍستروجين الأنثوي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, today as a trans person, public bathrooms and change rooms
اليوم وكشخص متحول جنسياً، تعتبر الحمامات العامة وغرف تبديل الملابس
are where I am most likely to be questioned or harassed.
أكثر الأماكن التي أتعرض فيها للإستجواب أو التحرش،
I've often been verbally attacked behind their doors.
وغالباً ما تعرضت للهجوم اللفظي خلف تلك الأبواب.
I've been hauled out by security guards with my pants still halfway pulled up.
سحبت للخارج من قبل بواسطة حراس الأمن وسروالي ما زال معلقاً على ساقي.
I've been stared at, screamed at, whispered about,
كان الناس يحدقون في، يصرخون على، ويتهامسون عني،
and one time I got smacked in the face by a little old lady's purse
وذات مرة تعرضت لصفعة على الوجه بمحفظة نقود سيدة مسنة
that from the looks of the shiner I took home that day
بسبب منظر الملمع الذي أخذته معي يومها
I am pretty certain contained at least 70 dollars of rolled up small change
حيث بكل تأكيد احتفظت ب 70 دولار متبقي الحساب
and a large hard candy collection.
ومجموعة كبيرة من الحلوى.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I know what some of you are thinking,
وأعلم ما يجول بخاطر بعضكم،
and you're mostly right.
وأنتم على صواب فعلاً.
I can and do just use the men's room most of the time these days.
حيث أني استخدم غرف الرجال فقط في كثير من الأوقات هذه الأيام.
But that doesn't solve my change room dilemmas, does it?
ولكن ذلك لا يحل معضلتي المتعلقة بغرف تبديل الملابس، أليس كذلك؟
And I shouldn't have to use the men's room because I'm not a man.
ويتوجب على ألا أستخدم غرف الرجال لأني لست رجلاً.
I'm a trans person.
أنا شخص متحول جنسياً.
And now we've got these fearmongering politicians
والآن ابتلينا بسياسيين يروجون للخوف
that keep trying to pass these bathroom bills.
والذين يحاولون تمرير مشروع قانون الحمام هذا.
Have you heard about these?
هل سمعتم عن هذا الأمر؟
They try to legislate to try and force people like myself
يحاولون فرض تشريع يرغم الأشخاص مثلي
to use the bathroom that they deem most appropriate
على استخدام الحمام الذي يرونه الأنسب على الإطلاق
according to the gender I was assigned at birth.
على حسب الجنس الذي حدد لي عند الولادة.
And if these politicians ever get their way,
واذا ما قدر لهم النجاح،
in Arizona or California or Florida
في أريزونا أو كاليفورنيا أو فلوريدا
or just last week in Houston, Texas,
أو كالأسبوع المنصرم في هوستون وتكساس
or Ottawa,
وأوتاوا،
well then, using the men's room will not be a legal option for me either.
حسناً، حينها لن يكون استخدام غرفة الرجال خياراً قانونياً بالنسبة لي حتى.
And every time one of these politicians brings one of these bills to the table,
وفي كل مرة يعرض فيها أحد هؤلاء السياسيين مشروع قانون كهذا على الطاولة،
I can't help but wonder, you know,
لا أملك غير أن أتعجب، أتعلمون،
just who will and exactly how would we go about enforcing laws like these. Right?
من الذي وتحديداً كيف لنا أن نفرض قوانين كهذه. أليس كذلك؟
Panty checks?
بالكشف على اللباس الداخلي؟
Really.
حقاً.
Genital inspections outside of bath change rooms at public pools?
بفحص الأعضاء التناسلية عند غرف تبديل الملابس في أحواض السباحة العامة؟
There's no legal or ethical or plausible way
ليس هناك من طريقة قانونية أو أخلاقية أو معقولة
to enforce laws like these anyway.
لفرض قوانين كهذه بأي شكل من الأشكال.
They exist only to foster fear
هي موجودة فقط لتعزيز الخوف
and promote transphobia.
وللترويج لكراهية التحول الجنسي.
They don't make anyone safer.
هي لا توفر الأمان لأحد.
But they do for sure make the world more dangerous for some of us.
ولكنها بالتأكيد تجعل العالم مكاناً أكثر خطورة بالنسبة للبعض منا.
And meanwhile, our trans children suffer.
وفي غضون ذلك، فإن أبناءنا يعانون.
They drop out of school, or they opt out of life altogether.
فهم يتركون المدارس، أو ينسحبون من الحياة ككل.
Trans people, especially trans and gender-nonconforming youth
المتحولون جنسياً وبخاصة الشباب منهم
face additional challenges when accessing pools and gyms,
يواجهون تحديات إضافية عند ذهابهم لأحواض السباحة والصالات الرياضية،
but also universities,
وكذلك الجامعات،
hospitals, libraries.
والمستشفيات والمكتبات.
Don't even get me started on how they treat us in airports.
من دون أن أخوض في طريقة معاملتهم لنا في المطارات.
If we don't move now
إن لم نتحرك الآن
to make sure that these places
لجعل هذه الأماكن
are truly open and accessible to everyone,
مفتوحة ومتاحة حقاً للجميع،
then we just need to get honest
حينها لابد أن نتحلى بالمصداقية
and quit calling them public places.
وأن نتوقف عن تسميتها بالأماكن العامة.
We need to just admit
نحن بحاجة أن نقر
that they are really only open for people
أنها مفتوحة فقط لأناس
who fit neatly into one of two gender boxes,
ينتمون بشكل كامل لأحد الجنسين،
which I do not.
الشيئ الذي لا أمثله.
I never have.
ولم أكن يوماً.
And this starts very early.
ولقد بدأ هذا الأمر مبكراً جداً.
I know a little girl. She's the daughter of a friend of mine.
أعرف فتاة صغيرة. هي بنت صديقة لي.
She's a self-identified tomboy.
تعرّف نفسها بأنها فتاة مسترجلة.
I'm talking about cowboy boots
أتحدث عن أحذية رعاة البقر
and Caterpillar yellow toy trucks and bug jars, the whole nine yards.
ولعب الشاحنات الصفراء الصغيرة ماركة Caterpillar، وقناني الحشرات وكل شيئ.
One time I asked her what her favorite color was.
ذات مرة سألتها عن لونها المفضل.
She told me, "Camouflage."
قالت لي: "التمويه."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So that awesome little kid,
تلك الفتاة الرائعة الصغيرة،
she came home from school last October
عادت إلى المنزل من المدرسة في إكتوبر الماضي
from her half day of preschool
بعد انقضاء نصف اليوم المدرسي
with soggy pants on because the other kids at school were harassing her
بسروال مبلل بسبب أن الأطفال الآخرين في المدرسة كانوا يتحرشون بها
when she tried to use the girls' bathroom.
عندما حاولت استخدام حمام الفتيات.
And the teacher had already instructed her to stay out of the boys' bathroom.
كما أن المدرس قد أمرها مسبقاً بالإبتعاد عن حمام الفتيان.
And she had drank two glasses of that red juice
أما هي فقد شربت كأسين من ذلك العصير الأحمر
at the Halloween party,
خلال الإحتفال بعيد الهالوين،
and I mean, who can resist that red juice, right? It's so good.
أقصد، من يستطيع مقاومة ذلك العصير الأحمر، أليس كذلك؟ فهو رائع جداً.
And she couldn't hold her pee any longer.
فلم تستطع التحكم في نفسها أكثر.
Her and her classmates were four years old.
كانت هي وأقرانها في الرابعة من العمر.
They already felt empowered enough
أما هم فقد شعروا بالسلطة الكافية
to police her use of the so-called public bathrooms.
لمراقبة استخدامها لما يسمى بالحمامات العامة.
She was four years old.
كانت في عمر الرابعة.
She had already been taught the brutal lesson
علّمت الدرس القاسي
that there was no bathroom door at preschool
والذي مفاده أنه لا يوجد باب حمام في الروضة
with a sign on it that welcomed people like her.
عليه علامة ترحب بالأشخاص مثلها.
She'd already learned that bathrooms were going to be a problem,
تعلمت أن دورات المياه في طريقها أن تكون مشكلة،
and that problem started with her
وأن تلك المشكلة بدأت معها
and was hers alone.
وهي مشكلتها وحدها.
So my friend asked me to talk to her little daughter,
لذلك طلبت مني صديقتي التحدث إلى بنتها الصغيرة،
and I did.
وقد كان.
I wanted to tell her
أردت أن أخبرها
that me and her mom were going to march on down
أني سأذهب بصحبة أمها
and talk to that school, and the problem was going to go away,
ونتحدث إلى القائمين على أمر تلك المدرسة، وسيتم حل المشلكة،
but I knew that wasn't true.
وكنت أعلم أن ذلك غير صحيح.
I wanted to tell her that it was all going to get better when she got older,
أردت أن أخبرها أن الأمور ستتحسن عندما تكبر،
but I couldn't.
ولكني لم أستطع.
So I asked her to tell me the story of what had happened,
لذلك طلبت منها أن تقص علي ما حدث،
asked her to tell me how it made her feel.
سألتها عن شعورها حيال الأمر.
"Mad and sad,"
"معتوهة وحزينة"
she told me.
أخبرتني هكذا.
So I told her
لذلك أخبرتها
that she wasn't alone
أنها ليست الوحيدة
and that it wasn't right what had happened to her,
وأن ما حدث لها ليس بالشيء الصحيح،
and then she asked me if I had ever peed in my pants before.
ثم سألتني إن حدث وتبولت على سروالي من قبل.
I said yes, I had,
فقلت نعم، حدث لي ذلك،
but not for a really long time.
ولكن ليس لوقت طويل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Which of course was a lie,
والتي بالطبع كانت كذبة،
because you know how you hit, like, 42 or 43,
لأنكم تعلمون
and sometimes you just, I don't know, you pee a little bit
وأحياناً فقط، لا أعلم، تنزل منكم بعض القطرات
when you cough or sneeze,
حينما تكحون أو تعطسون،
when you're running upstairs, or you're stretching.
عندما تهرولون على الدرج، أو حينما تتمددون.
Don't lie.
لا تكذبوا.
It happens. Right?
فهذا يحدث. أليس كذلك؟
She doesn't need to know that, I figure.
حسبت أنها ليست بحاجة أن تعرف ذلك،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I told her, when you get older, your bladder is going to grow bigger, too.
أخبرتها، عندما تكبرين، فإن مثانتك تكبر أيضاً.
When you get old like me,
عندما تصبحين في عمري،
you're going to be able to hold your pee for way longer,
سيصبح بمقدورك التحكم في نفسك لفترة أطول،
I promised her.
وعدتها بذلك.
"Until you can get home?"
"إلى حين وصولي البيت؟"
she asked me.
سألتني.
I said, "Yes,
فقلت: "نعم
until you can get home."
إلى حين وصولك البيت."
She seemed to take some comfort in that.
بدا أن ذلك يريحها بعض الشيئ.
So let's just build some single stall, gender-neutral bathrooms
لذلك، هيا نبني حمامات خاصة بأحاديي الجنس
with a little bench for getting changed into your gym clothes.
مزودة بمقعد لتغيير الملابس.
We can't change the world overnight
لا نستطيع تغيير العالم بين ليلة وضحاها
for our children,
من أجل صغارنا،
but we can give them a safe and private place
ولكن نستطيع أن نمدهم بمكان آمن ويوفر الخصوصية
to escape that world,
حتى يهربوا من ذلك العالم،
if only for just a minute.
ولو حتى لدقيقة واحدة.
This we can do.
هذا ما نستطيع فعله.
So let's just do it.
لذا هيا بنا نفعل ذلك.
And if you are one of those people who is sitting out there right now
وإذا ما كنت أحد أولئك الأشخاص الذين يجلسون خارج المكان حالياً
already coming up with a list of reasons in your head why this is not a priority,
وفي ذهنك قائمة من الأسباب لم قد يكون هذا بالشيئ الضروري،
or it's too expensive,
أو أنه مكلف جداً،
or telling yourself that giving a trans person a safe place to pee
أو قولك لنفسك أن توفير مكان آمن للشخص المتحول جنسياً للتبول
or get changed in
أو تغيير الملابس
supports a lifestyle choice that you feel offends your morality,
يدعم إختيار نمط حياة تشعر أنه يسيئ إلى أخلاقك،
or your masculinity,
أو ذكوريتك،
or your religious beliefs,
أو معتقداتك الدينية،
then let me just appeal
إذاً اسمح لي أن أناشد
to the part of your heart that probably, hopefully,
الجزء من قلبك الذي من المحتمل والمؤمل
does care about the rest of the population.
أنه يراعي لبقية السكان.
If you can't bring yourself to care enough about people like me,
اذا لم يكن بمقدورك أن تراعي بما يكفي الأشخاص مثلي،
then what about women and girls
فماذا عن النساء والفتيات
with body image issues?
اللواتي يعانين من صورة أجسادهن؟
What about anyone with body image stuff going on?
ماذا عن أي شخص يعاني جراء صورة جسده؟
What about that boy at school who is a foot shorter than his classmates,
ماذا عن ذلك الفتى الأقصر من أقرانه في المدرسة،
whose voice still hasn't dropped yet? Hey?
الذي لايجد صوتاً يدافع به بعد؟
Oh, grade eight,
في الصف الثامن،
what a cruel master you can be.
أي مدرس قاسي لك أن تكون.
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
What about people with anxiety issues?
ماذا عن الذين يعانون من القلق؟
What about people with disabilities or who need assistance in there?
ماذا عن ذوي الحاجات الخاصة أو الذين يحتاجون إلى المساعدة؟
What about folks with bodies who, for whatever reason,
ماذا عن القوم الذين ولأي سبب كان،
don't fit into the mainstream idea of what a body should look like?
لا ينسجمون مع الفكرة السائدة حول ما يجب أن يبدو عليه الجسد؟
How many of us still feel shy
كم منا لا يزال يشعر بالخجل
or afraid to disrobe in front of our peers,
أو الخوف من خلع ملابسنا أمام أقراننا،
and how many of us allow that fear
وكم منَّا يسمح لذلك الخوف
to keep us from something as important
بحرماننا من شيئ مهم
as physical exercise?
كالتمارين الرياضية؟
Would all those people not benefit
ألن يستفيد كل هؤلاء الناس
from these single stall facilities?
من هذه المرافق المنفصلة؟
We can't change transphobic minds overnight,
ليس بوسعنا التاثير على العقول المهووسة بفكرة التحول الجنسي بين ليلة وضحاها،
but we can give everybody
ولكن بوسعنا مد أي أحد
a place to get changed in
بمكان يغير فيه ملابسه
so that we can all get to work
بذلك نستطيع العودة والعمل
making the world safer
من أجل عالم أكثر أماناً
for all of us.
لنا جميعاً.
Thank you for listening.
شكراً لحسن إصغائكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.